{"tossups": [{"question": "<b>This campaign featured the Battle of the Pips, in which two ships fired into an empty sea because their radar confused birds for enemy vessels. As part of this campaign\u2019s Operation Cottage, the United States bombarded a target non-stop for three weeks, then invaded,</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>only to discover the enemy had left before the bombardment. In this campaign, the</b> <b>intelligence agents of Castner\u2019s Cutthroats helped construct the Adak Island landing strip. This campaign began with an attack on (*) </b> Dutch Harbor that coincided with the Battle of Midway. Attu and Kiska were the targets of, for the points, what World War II campaign over islands in the far north Pacific?", "answer": "<b> Aleutian</b> Islands Campaign (accept descriptions of the<b> Alaska</b>n theater of World War II; prompt on descriptions of (the Pacific theater of) World War II before mentioned) (2) <b>A song about the leaders of one of these events has him throw his newly married</b> <b>bride into a river to prove his devotion to his cause. That leader, Stepan Razin, captured</b> <b>Astrakhan and drew on the support of the (+)</b> <b>Don Cossacks. Another leader of one of</b> <b>these events was struck from the historical record after his defeat and conquered Kazan. That leader styled himself (*)</b> Tsar Peter III before being defeated at Tsaritsyn and forced into an iron cage before Catherine the Great. For the points, name this type of uprising led by Pugachev, drawing on the frustrations of repressed serfs. ANSWER: Russian<b> peasant rebellion</b> (accept<b> serf rebellion</b>,<b> Cossack uprising</b> before Cossacks)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>During the 2000 presidential campaign, this man criticized George W. Bush by saying\u201cwe do not want another candidate who needs on-the-job training.\u201d During Reagan\u2019s entire presidency, this man served as a Senator from (+) Indiana. This man became the subject of much ridicule after an incident at Mu\u02dcnoz Rivera Elementary School, where he (*)</b> added an\u201ce\u201d to the end of \u201cpotato\u201d at a spelling bee. In 1992, Al Gore competed in a debate with, for the points, what man who served as Vice President under George H.W. Bush?", "answer": "Danforth \u201cDan\u201d<b> Quayle</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The Oxford Library acquired this philosopher\u2019s personal papers in the Lovelace Collection in the mid-1940s. As the secretary of Anthony Ashley Cooper, Earl of Shaftesbury, this man wrote the</b><em><b> Fundamental</b></em><b> (+)</b><em><b> Constitutions of Carolina</b></em><b>. This man rebutted Robert Filmer\u2019s </b><em><b>Patriarcha</b></em><b> in a work holding that the right to revolution is embodied in the social contract. This man\u2019s belief that governments should protect (*) </b> life, liberty, and property influenced the U.S. Constitution. For the points, name this author of<em> Two Treatises of Government</em>.", "answer": "John<b> Locke</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man requested a 500,000 dollar loan from the British diplomat Anthony Merry. Two men working under this person were charged of treason in the case of (+)</b><em><b> Ex parte Bollman</b></em><b>. An expedition led by this man created a base of operations on Harman Blennerhassett\u2019s island in the Ohio River. A letter from James Wilkinson to (*)</b> Thomas Jefferson revealed that this man was plotting the creation of an independent empire in the southern U.S. For the points, name this former vice president who led an abortive 1807 conspiracy.", "answer": "Aaron<b> Burr</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>In its early service, Richard Kempenfelt commanded this ship and cut supplies headed to the Indies by capturing a convoy at the Second Battle of Ushant. This flagship was given an iconic black and yellow (+) \u201cchequer\u201d pattern prior to its last battle. At the 1797 Battle of Cape St. Vincent, this ship dueled the</b><em><b> Santisima Trinidad</b></em><b> for the first time; when they dueled again eight years later, this ship sent the message (*)</b> \u201cEngland expects every man will do his duty\u201d and led an attack against a Franco-Spanish column. For the points, name the flagship of Horatio Nelson at Trafalgar.", "answer": "HMS<b> Victory</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>A religious work with this name mentions two namesake martyrs: a woman with seven sons and a man named Eleazer. A leader of a group with this name defeated Lysias at the battle of Emmaus while another member of that group was succeeded by John (+) Hyrcanus after his assassination. One book with this name describes the desecration of the Second Temple by Antiochus IV, which triggers a namesake revolt against the (*)</b> Seleucid Empire by a group with this name. For the points, what name was shared between a group of Jewish rebels who established the Hasmonean dynasty and a series of deuterocanonical books also titled for the namesake group?", "answer": "<b> Maccabees</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "In 2014, this city opened the Center for Civil and Human Rights, a project campaigned for by former mayor Andrew Young. (*)</b> Eric Robert Rudolph injured over 100 people with a bomb planted in, for the points, what city\u2019s Centennial Olympic Park in 1996 during the Summer Olympics?", "answer": "<b> Atlanta</b> Page 3", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>In 1903, Ludwig Roselius invented a version of this good without its central ingredient. Augustus the Strong donated a sculpture to a place that sold this good showing a (+) Turk offering it to Cupid. In 1976, a critical shortage of this good forced Erich Honecker\u2019s East German government to buy a large surplus of it. This good, which was celebrated in a namesake (*)</b> Bach cantata celebrating it. Public opinion arose in the 18th century from discussions held during communal consumption of, for the points, what beverage that was introduced to Germany in the 17th century and sold in caf\u00b4es?", "answer": "<b> coffee</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>One of these objects is pinned to the shirt of the rightmost figure in Caravaggio\u2019s</b><em><b> Supper</b></em> <em><b>at Emmaus</b></em><b>, as it symbolizes Cleopas\u2019 status as a pilgrim to (+)</b> <b>Santiago de Compostela.</b> <b>These objects were associated with Saint James and are often present in Anadyomene depictions of a certain goddess. A gigantic one of these objects holds the title figure as (*) </b>she is blown to shore by Zephyr in Botticelli\u2019s<em> Birth of Venus</em>. Mother of pearl and abalone are derived from, for the points, what hard coverings of molluscs?", "answer": "scallop<b> shell</b>s (or<b> seashell</b>s)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>After 1906, every Supreme Court Justice has signed a Bible donated by this man. This man attacked a \u201cthin disguise\u201d that \u201cwill not mislead anyone, nor atone for the wrong this day done.\u201d This man noted that \u201cthere is a (+) race so different from our own that we do not permit\u201d them to be citizens, yet they are not excluded by Louisiana\u2019s (*)</b> Separate Car Act; that argument was posed in this man\u2019s argument that an 1896 case would be \u201cas pernicious as [...] the Dred Scott case.\u201d For the points, name this Supreme Court justice, the lone dissenter in<em> Plessy v.</em> <em>Ferguson</em>.", "answer": "John Marshall<b> Harlan</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This architect created a building comprised of stacked cubes on an artificial peninsula in Doha that houses the Qatar Museum of Islamic Art. With James Freed, this architect</b> <b>designed the Crystal Palace-inspired (+)</b> <b>Javits Convention Center in Manhattan. This</b> <b>man designed an addition for the Cour Napoleon on commission from Fran\u00b8cois Mitterand, which consists of an (*) </b> underground lobby contained in a large glass structure made of over 600 triangular panes. For the points, name this Chinese-American architect of the Louvre Pyramid.", "answer": "Ieoh Ming \u201cI.M.\u201d<b> Pei</b> Page 4", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {"question": "<b>The first of these conflicts began when an officer took offense at a delayed salute and opened fire at the Goodwin Sands. During one of these conflicts, a king lit celebratory bonfires after Robert Holmes sacked the city of Tershelling. During the second of these conflicts, one side\u2019s navy broke through the (+) Chatham Dockyard and destroyed eighteen ships anchored in the Medway River. During one of these wars, Michiel de (*)</b> Ruyter [mik-eel de RAO-ter] commanded a navy during the Four Days\u2019 Battle fought shortly before the Great Fire of London. For the points, name this series of 17th century wars between two maritime powers, one ruled by the Stuarts and the other by the House of Orange.", "answer": "<b> Anglo-Dutch</b> Wars (accept descriptions of wars between<b> England</b>, the<b> United Kingdom</b>, etc., and the<b> Dutch</b> Republic, the<b> Batavian</b> Republic, the Republic of the Seven United<b> Netherlands</b>, etc.) (19) <b>This man\u2019s autobiography and one of his albums are both titled</b><em><b> Bound for Glory</b></em><b>.</b> <b>This musician wrote about an individual who saw his people \u201cBy the relief office\u201d in a song written in response to Irving Berlin\u2019s \u201cGod Bless America.\u201d This man, who collected songs</b> <b>like (+)</b> <b>\u201cPretty Boy Floyd\u201d and \u201cTom Joad\u201d in his</b><em><b> Dust Bowl Ballads</b></em><b>, is best known for</b> <b>a song about a place that stretches \u201cfrom the red wood forest to the (*)</b> Gulf Stream waters.\u201dThe words \u201cThis machine kills fascists\u201d were written on the guitar of, for the points, what American folk singer and songwriter of \u201cThis Land is Your Land?\u201d ANSWER: Woody<b> Guthrie</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This animal was unsuccessfully reintroduced to Maria Island as the founding population died out in the 1990s. The first European to report the existence of this animal was captain</b> <b>Willem de Vlamingh in 1696. An (+)</b> <b>egg of this animal was supposedly thrown into the</b> <b>sky and formed the sun, according to one Gamilaraay creation myth. G.P.W. Meredith led a group of farmers in an (*) </b> ambush against these animals, which utterly failed after their Lewis guns jammed and only twelve of these animals were shot. Sir George Pearce was nicknamed the minister of a 1932 war against, for the points, what flightless, farm-invading birds endemic to Australia?", "answer": "<b> emu</b>s", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>A loyalist gang in this state was known as \u201cBacon\u2019s Refugees.\u201d Following an event in this state involving the capture of Joshua Huddy, George Washington declared that Charles Asgill would be executed. The Forage Wars took place in this state which the Quintipartite</b> <b>Deed split into two halves, divided by the (+)</b> <b>Keith Line. This state\u2019s city of Elizabeth</b> <b>was named for the wife of George Carteret. The Continental Army set up winter quarters at this state\u2019s town of (*)</b> Morristown after it crossed the Delaware River. William Franklin served as colonial governor of, for the points, what state where the Battle of Trenton was fought?", "answer": "<b> New Jersey</b> Page 5", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>A leader of this country led the Radepa faction and was thrown from a balcony after Plaza Murillo was seized. Another leader of this country led the Lanza regiment at the Battle of Gondra and was Germ\u00b4an Busch. This country, which faced the Catavi miners massacre, was led by the supposedly pro-fascist (+) Gualberto Villaroel. The German Hans Kundt was made general by a ruler of this country named Daniel Salamanca. This country, which lost the First Battle of (*)</b> Nanawa, relied on Quechua and Aymar\u00b4a troops from the Altiplano in one war. For the points, name this South American nation that was defeated by Paraguay in the Gran Chaco War.", "answer": "<b> Bolivia</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>The anniversary of this event is commemorated as Double Ten Day. The mishandling of the Railway Protection movement sparked this event and culminated in the Battle of Yangxia. The forces of the Tongmenghui played a key role in this event, which begun with</b> <b>the (+)</b> <b>the (+)</b> <b>Wuchang Uprising. Yuan Shikai used the Beiyang Army to become provisional</b> <b>(*)</b> President during this event and forced the abdication of Emperor Puyi. For the points, name this President during this event and forced the abdication of Emperor Puyi. For the points, name this revolution led by Sun Yat-Sen which ended the Qing Dynasty and led to the establishment of the Republic of China.", "answer": "<b> Xinhai</b> Revolution (accept<b> Chinese Revolution of 1911</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Domagaya taught this man how to make what was probably spruce beer to cure scurvy. At the Islands of the Birds, this man\u2019s crew killed around 1000 birds, many of which were Great Auks. This man, who captured two natives at Honguedo, named a water formation he found for China, the (+) Lachine [la-sheen] Rapids. Jean Fran\u00b8cois Roberval hired this man as Chief Navigator. This man kidnaped Chief Donnacona in the hope that he could find the Kingdom of Saguenay. The phrase (*)</b> \u201cAs false as Canadian diamonds,\u201d refers to the two shiploads of fool\u2019s gold that this man brought home to France. For the points, name this explorer who sailed up the St. Lawrence River for Francis I and named Canada.", "answer": "Jacques<b> Cartier</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b>While serving on the Third Court of the Appeals, this justice argued for the vacating of a law that banned Raymond Rybar from owning a machine gun. This justice argued that\u201cnational commitment to free and open debate is not a license for the vicious verbal assault\u201dconducted by the (+) Westboro Baptist Church. This justice, the only dissenter in</b><em><b> Snyder</b></em> <em><b>v. Phelps</b></em><b>, was appointed to the Supreme Court in 2005 after the retirement of (*)</b> Sandra Day O\u2019Connor. A voting block of Clarence Thomas, John Roberts, and this man leans conservative on the current Court. For the points, name this Supreme Court justice, the second justice of Italian-American descent in Court history.", "answer": "Samuel Anthony<b> Alito</b> Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>While working as an operative for this group, Donald Segretti helped forge a document alleging that Edmund Muskie disliked French-Canadians, known as the Canuck Letter. A</b> <b>check linked to (+)</b> <b>Kenneth Dahlberg, a member of this organization, contributed to its</b> <b>downfall. John N. Mitchell led this group, which often collaborated with (*)</b> \u201cthe Plumbers.\u201dG. Gordon Liddy and E. Howard Hunt were members of, for the points, what committee that engaged in illegal activities against President Nixon\u2019s political opponents to, ostensibly, accomplish their title goal?", "answer": "<b> Committee for the Re-election of the President</b> (accept<b> CRP</b> or<b> CREEP</b>; accept descriptions of Richard<b> Nixon\u2019s re-election campaign</b>; prompt on descriptions of a Watergate Committee, but do not accept or prompt on related answers that include the word \u201cSenate;\u201d do not accept or prompt on the Plumbers) Page 7", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This man and Roger Penrose developed a theorem that states that if there is a trapped null surface and a nonnegative energy density, then there exist finite length geodesics that can\u2019t be extended. In 1997, this scientist joined (+) Kip Thorne on a public wager against John Preskill concerning the information paradox. This man, whose thesis was based on extending the (*)</b> singularity theorem of black holes to the entire universe, was the author of<em> A Brief</em> <em>History of Time</em>. For the points, name this British physicist who passed away in March of 2018.", "answer": "Stephen<b> Hawking</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {"question": "<b>The leader of this empire fired a cannon to signal his safe arrival at Vishalgad following the Battle of Pavan Khind. Alam II was installed in his highest post by a leader of this</b> <b>empire whose victory at Udgir was a major blow to the Nizam of (+)</b> <b>Hyderabad. The</b> <b>Durrani Empire defeated the forces of Sadashivrao Bhau during a 1761 battle lost by this empire. This empire, which was ruled by</b><em><b> peshwas</b></em><b>, was revived by Madhavrao after its humiliating defeat at the Third Battle of (*) </b> Panipat. The founder of this empire was born in a fort in Maharashtra. Shivaji led, for the points, what confederacy that dominated 18th century India?", "answer": "<b> Maratha</b> Confederacy (or Empire)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Charles White Whittlesey earned a Medal of Honor for leading an inexperienced force at this battle that was cut off from supplies or reinforcements for five days. During the first phase of this battle, the \u201cBuckeye Division\u201d led a failed attempt to capture Montfaucon.</b> <b>The (+)</b> <b>\u201cLost Battalion\u201d fought at this battle, where 132 troops were captured by (*)</b> Alvin York. The Advance to the Meuse was part of the final phase of this battle that ended on November 11, 1918. For the points, name this battle in the final Allied offensive of World War I that took place in a French forest.", "answer": "Battle of the<b> Argonne</b> Forest (accept Meuse-<b>Argonne</b> Offensive) Page 9", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>In the 1870s, members of Ferdinand Hayden\u2019s expedition in this region built a ranch around Liberty Cap. Nathaniel Langford was the first official overseer of this location, for which Columbus Delano organized a government-funded survey. A 1963 report by (+) Aldo Leopold suggested culling the elk population in this region. Harry Yount became gamekeeper of this region after exploring the nearby (*)</b> Grand Tetons. An 1872 Act of Dedication defined and established this location, where Camp Sheridan was established around the Mammoth Hot Springs. For the points, name this home of Old Faithful, the first American national park.", "answer": "<b> Yellowstone</b> National Park", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In this western state, Frank Wolcott and former sheriff Frank Canton led a murderous group of \u201cRegulators\u201d at the behest of business interests. Benjamin Harrison sent the Sixth</b> <b>Cavalry to this state to protect a group of gunmen hiding at the TA Ranch on (+)</b> <b>Crazy</b> <b>Women Creek. In April 1892 in the northeastern portion of this state, large ranchers hired a band of killers to murder smaller ranchers they accused of cattle rustling throughout the (*) </b> Powder River Basin. For the points, name this state that was home to the Johnson County War perpetrated by powerful ranchers like the members of the Cheyenne Club.", "answer": "<b> Wyoming</b> Page 10", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}